so let's do the solution to our BTB and
BHT quiz we have a BHT with 16 entries
which gives perfect predictions we have
a bt b with 4 entries gives us perfect
predictions the question was how many
times do we access the BHT for each of
these instructions we access the BHT in
order to tell us whether this
instruction is a taken branch we do that
every time we fetch an instruction and
because we have a perfect prediction for
both Bhd and the BTB
that means that we will never fail
instruction that actually is not
supposed to execute so we now just need
to figure out how many times each of
these instructions execute this
instruction here initializes r2 to 100
and that instruction executes only one
time once we are done executing it we
will go into the loop loop here and then
exit never coming back here same here
this puts zero in our one that executed
only once now we have a loop this loop
will execute as long as r1 and r2 are
different
r1 initially has a zero value goes
through here gets incremented and then
we branch back now we execute this loop
once more with r1 being equal to 1 and
then 2 3 etc the last iteration we do
will be with r1 equal 99 and finally our
1 will be incremented we jump back here
find out that r1 and r2 are now the same
because r1 is now 100 and exit the loop
so there is a hundred iterations of this
loop and each of these instructions thus
executes 100 times this instruction here
executes saundra times when we are
staying in the loop and once we for the
hundredth time jump back it executes
once more in order to exit the loop so
this instruction executes for 101 times
and each time any of these instructions
execute we are going to access the BHT
to see whether that instruction is an
taken branch or not